{
    "id": "39e1812985f948448ad52190dcf821ac",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The boy ..................................... for stealing.",
            "description": "The boy did not punish he was punished (by somebody else). With the other options, an object would be required to make the sentence complete.",
            "answers": [
                "punished",
                "has punished",
                "was punished"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bf7947f8a05041a3889499a0ada7c34b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................... him for several years.",
            "description": "We normally use perfect tenses with the time expressions since and for. ",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knew",
                "have known"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "90672a9b345f4f9ba9f31314daa9ec09"
        },
        {
            "question": "...................................... he continue to be unpunctual, he shall be dismissed.",
            "description": "'Should he continue' here means 'if he continues'.",
            "answers": [
                "Could",
                "Would",
                "Should"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ac4c258c96ad4755b5dc8540794e953b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Had he told me earlier, I ...................................... arranged it.",
            "description": "The given sentence is in the third conditional. Here we use would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "would have",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4e41fb7adaf747f7bb36b7076cc0b2bb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If that man had drank less, he .................................... developed heart trouble.",
            "description": "The given sentence is in the third conditional. Here we use would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not",
                "would not",
                "would not have"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3c19aa6025474bffa6eb491afe6ea3f3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The minister .......................................... the foundation stone of the school.",
            "description": "Lied is simple past tense and past participle of lie. Laid is the second form of lay (to keep).",
            "answers": [
                "lay",
                "lied",
                "laid"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1dc5772427d94185b6f3f60dbc4199cb"
        },
        {
            "question": "All the expenses .................................... by the company.",
            "description": "'By' indicates passive voice. 'Was/were + third form of the verb' is used in the passive voice of simple past tense. 'Expenses' is plural and hence we use 'were' here. ",
            "answers": [
                "bore",
                "borne",
                "was borne",
                "were borne"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "44cf657abf354c0dbecdc9c92738e94b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whenever he is in Mumbai, my father ..................................... with us.",
            "description": "'Whenever' indicates a routine. We use the present simple to talk about habits and routines. ",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "stays",
                "is staying"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9bb9decc3be0496c973e61628a71259a"
        },
        {
            "question": "When I visited him, he ...................................... bedridden for two months.",
            "description": "The past perfect continuous is used to talk about an action that started in the past and continued up to later moment in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "78e1af4ce8e04b7cb9a6415af8e071e6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you when dinner ......................................... ready.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to indicate future. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "is",
                "would be"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ad701ccb94c24dee811d62f79fb8d8ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "The war ........................................ for two years, when John enlisted.",
            "description": "The past perfect continuous is used to talk about an action that started in the past and continued up to later moment in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "was going on",
                "has been going on",
                "had been going on"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "45426ff9afe34293adfbf6b52dba8dbc"
        },
        {
            "question": "............................................ the message, the man departed.",
            "description": "The man departed after he had given the message. This is best expressed by the use of the phrase 'having given'. ",
            "answers": [
                "Giving",
                "Given",
                "Having given",
                "Having been given"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ccbff3bb98594e9b8d348e1978b16f5b"
        }
    ]
}